Inventory of the Russian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File (third installment) (Boxes 32-45)
  - Commonwealth of Independent States - Russia (Federation)
    - Elections, 1992-2001
      - Parliamentary, 1993-1999
        - 1995 December 17
          - Distribution of votes in the Federal Electoral District
            (Arranged numerically by election association number in ballot order)
            - 1. Zhenshchiny Rossii (Box-folder 33: 5)
            - 2. Derzhava (Box-folder 33: 6)
            - 3. Duma – 96 (Box-folder 33: 7)
            - 4. Preobrazhenie otechestva (Box-folder 33: 8)
            - 5. Tikhonov-Tupolev-Tikhonov (Box-folder 33: 9)
            - 6. Rossiiskoe obshchenarodnoe dvizhenie (Box-folder 33: 10)
            - 7. Obshcherossiiskoe musul'manskoe dvizhenie (Box-folder 33: 11)
            - 8. Federal'no- demokraticheskoe dvizhenie (Box-folder 33: 12)
            - 9. Predvybornyi blok, vkliuchaiushchii rukovoditelei Partii zashchity detei (Mira, dobra i schast'ia), Partii "Russkie zhenshchiny," Partii pravoslavnykh (Very, Nadezhdy, Liubvi), Narodnoi khristiansko-monarkhicheskoi partii, Partii za soiuz slavianskikh narodov, Partii sel'skikh truzhenikov "Zemlia-matushka," partii zashchity invalidov, partii postradavshikh ot vlastei i obezdolennykh (Delo Petra I) (Box-folder 33: 13)
            - 10. Mezhnatsional'nyi soiuz protiv vsekh (Box-folder 33: 14)
            - 11. Stabil'naia Rossiia (Box-folder 33: 15)
            - 12. Pokoleniia rubezha (Box-folder 33: 16)
            - 13. Moe otechestvo (Box-folder 33: 17)
            - 14. Za rodinu! (Box-folder 33: 18)
            - 15. Obshchee delo (Box-folder 33: 19)
            - 16. Blok nezavisimykh (Box-folder 33: 20)
            - 17. Nash dom – Rossiia (Box-folder 33: 21)
            - 18. Pamfilova - Gurov – Lysenko (PGL) (Box-folder 34: 1)
            - 19. Yabloko (Box-folder 34: 2)
            - 20. Vpered, Rossiia! (Box-folder 34: 3)
            - 21. 89 (89 regionov Rossii) (Box-folder 34: 4)
            - 22. Kedr (Box-folder 34: 5)
            - 23. Demokraticheskii vybor Rossii – obedinennye demokraty (Box-folder 34: 6)
            - 24. Partiia Rossiiskogo edinstva i soglasiia (PRES) (Box-folder 34: 7)
            - 25. Kommunisticheskaia partiia Rossiiskoi Federatsii (KPRF) (Box-folder 34: 8)
            - 26. Blok Stanislava Govorukhina (Box-folder 34: 9)
            - 27. Assotsiatsiia advokatov Rossii (Box-folder 34: 10)
            - 28. Natsional'no-respulikanskaia partiia Rossii (NRPR) (Box-folder 34: 11)
            - 29. Sotsial-demokraty (Box-folder 34: 12)
            - 30. Vlast' – narodu (Box-folder 34: 13)
            - 31. Kongress russkikh obshchin (KRO) (Box-folder 34: 14)
            - 32. Profsoiuzy i promyshlenniki Rossii – Soiuz Truda (Box-folder 34: 15)
            - 33. Liberal'no-demokraticheskaia partiia Rosii (LDPR) (Box-folder 34: 16)
            - 34. Partiia zashchity zdravokhranenia, obrazovaniia, nauki i kul'tury, partiia zashchity molodezhi, obedinenia nezavisimykh profsoiuzov, partii spravedlivosti, partii okhrany prirody (Dzhuna) (Box-folder 34: 17)
            - 35. Partiia samoupravleniia trudiashchikhsia (PST) (Box-folder 34: 18)
            - 36. Kommunisty, trudovaia Rossiia – Za Sovetskii Soiuz (Box-folder 34: 19)
            - 37. Partiia liubitelei piva (Box-folder 34: 20)
            - 38. Blok Ivana Rybkina (Box-folder 34: 21)
            - 39. Partiia ekonomicheskoi svobody (PES) (Box-folder 34: 22)
            - 40. Partiia "Narodnyi soiuz" (Box-folder 34: 23)
            - 41. Agrarnaia partiia Rossii (APR) (Box-folder 34: 24)
            - 42. Khristiansko-demokraticheskii Soiuz – Khristiane Rossii (Box-folder 34: 25)
        - Interim, 1998 (Box-folder 35: 1)
        - 1999 December 19
          - General (Box-folder 35: 2-5)
          - General (Box-folder 36: 1-5)
          - 1. Konservativnoe dvizhenie Rossii (Box-folder 36: 6)
          - 2. Rossiiskii obshchenarodnyi soiuz (Box-folder 36: 7)
          - 3. Zhenshchiny Rossii (Box-folder 36: 8)
          - 5. Stalinskii blok – za SSSR (Box-folder 37: 1)
          - 6. Obedinenie "Yabloko" (Box-folder 37: 2)
          - 7. Kommunisty, trudiashchiesia Rossii – za Sovetskii Soiuz (Box-folder 37: 3)
          - 8. Mir, Trud, Mai (Box-folder 37: 4)
          - 9. Blok generala Andreia Nikolaeva, akademika Sviatoslava Fedorova (Box-folder 37: 5)
          - 10. Vserossiiskoe obshchestvenno-politicheskoe dvizhenie "Dukhovnoe nasledie" (Box-folder 37: 6)
          - 11. Kongress russkikh obshchin I dvizhenie Yuriia Boldyreva (Box-folder 37: 7)
          - 12. Partiia mira i edinstva (Box-folder 37: 8)
          - 13. Rossiiskaia partiia zashchity zhenshchin (Box-folder 37: 9)
          - 14. Mezhregional'noe dvizhenie "Edinstvo" ("Medved'") (Box-folder 37: 10)
          - 16. Obshcherossiiskoe politicheskoe dvizhenie "V podderzhku armii" (Box-folder 37: 11)
          - 17. Blok Zhirinovskogo (Box-folder 37: 12)
          - 18. Za grazhdanskoe dostoinstvo (Box-folder 37: 13)
          - 19. Otechestvo – vsia Rossiia (Box-folder 37: 14)
          - 20. Kommunistichrskaia partiia Rossiiskoi Federatsii (Box-folder 37: 15)
          - 21. Russkoe delo (Box-folder 37: 16)
          - 23. Soiuz pravykh sil (Box-folder 37: 17)
          - 25. Vsesoiuznoe obshchestvenno-polichiskoe dvizhenie "Nash dom – Rossiia" (Box-folder 37: 18)
          - 26. Sotsial-demokraticheskaia partiia Rossii (Box-folder 37: 19)
          - 27. Partiia pensionerov (Box-folder 37: 20)
          - 28. Russkaia sotsialisticheskaia partiia (Box-folder 37: 21)
          - 29. Rossiiskaia konservativnaia partiia predprinimatelei (Box-folder 37: 22)
      - Presidential, 1996-2000
        - 1996 June 16
          - General
            - General (Box-folder 38: 1)
            - Altai (Box-folder 38: 2)
            - Stavropol' (Box-folder 38: 3)
            - Volgograd (Box-folder 38: 4)
          - Bryntsalov, Vladimir (Box-folder 38: 5)
          - Fedorov, Sviatoslav (Box-folder 38: 6)
          - Gorbachev, Mikhail (Box-folder 38: 7)
          - IAavlinskii, Grigorii (Box-folder 38: 8)
          - Lebed', Aleksandr (Box-folder 38: 9)
          - Maslov, Nikolai (Box-folder 38: 10)
          - Shakkum, Martin (Box-folder 39: 1)
          - Yeltsin, Boris (Box-folder 39: 2-3)
          - Zhirinovskii, Vladimir (Box-folder 39: 4)
          - Ziuganov, Gennadii (Box-folder 39: 5-6)
        - 2000, March 26
          - General
            - General (Box-folder 39: 7)
            - Govorukhin, Stanislav (Box-folder 40: 1)
            - Podberezkin, Aleksei (Box-folder 40: 2)
            - Putin, Vladimir (Box-folder 40: 3)
            - Skuratov, Yurii (Box-folder 40: 4)
            - Titov, Konstantin (Box-folder 40: 5)
            - Tuleev, Aman (Box-folder 40: 6)
            - Yavlinskii, Grigorii (Box-folder 40: 7)
            - Zhirinovskii, Vladimir (Box-folder 40: 8)
            - Ziuganov, Gennadii (Box-folder 40: 9)
          - Election Observation Mission to Russian Federation (ODIHR) (Box-folder 40: 10)
        - Miscellany
      - Local (Box-folder 40: 11)
        - General (City councils, mayors)
          - Altai (Barnaul), 1996 March 31 (Box-folder 40: 12)
          - Leningrad region, 1997 December 14 (Box-folder 40: 13)
          - Moscow
            - 1993 December 12 (Box-folder 40: 14)
            - 1997 December 14 (Box-folder 40: 15-16)
            - 1997 December 14 (Box-folder 41: 1)
            - 1999 December 12 (Box-folder 41: 2)
            - 2000 April 16 (Box-folder 41: 3)
            - 2001 December 16 (Box-folder 41: 4)
          - Novosibirsk, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 41: 5)
          - Perm, 1996 (Box-folder 41: 6)
          - Saint Petersburg
            - 1994 March 20 (Box-folder 41: 7)
            - 1994 March 20 (Box-folder 42: 1)
            - 1997 September 28 (Box-folder 42: 2-4)
            - 1998 December 6 (Box-folder 42: 5)
            - 1998 December 6 (Box-folder 43: 1-3)
            - 1999 December 19 (Box-folder 43: 4)
            - 2000 May 14 (Box-folder 43: 5)
          - Vologda (Box-folder 43: 6)
          - Vologda (Box-folder 44: 1)
        - Gubernatorial, 1996-1997
          - Briansk region (Box-folder 44: 2)
          - Evreiskii region (Box-folder 44: 3)
          - Kamchatka (Box-folder 44: 4)
          - Khabarovskii region (Box-folder 44: 5)
          - Koriakskii Autonomous Region (Box-folder 44: 6)
          - Krasnodar region (Box-folder 44: 7)
          - Leningrad region (Box-folder 44: 8)
          - Magadan (Box-folder 44: 9)
          - Moscow region (Box-folder 44: 10-11)
          - Murmansk (Box-folder 44: 12)
          - Nizhnii Novgorod (Box-folder 44: 13)
          - Pskov (Box-folder 44: 14)
          - Saint Petersburg (Box-folder 44: 15)
          - Saint Petersburg (Box-folder 45: 1)
          - Sakhalin (Box-folder 45: 2)
          - Stavropol' (Box-folder 45: 3)
          - Sverdlovskii region (Box-folder 45: 4)
          - Tiumen' (Box-folder 45: 5)
          - Tomsk (Box-folder 45: 6)
          - Tula (Box-folder 45: 7)
          - Vladimir (Box-folder 45: 8)
          - Volgograd region (Box-folder 45: 9)
          - Yakutiia (Box-folder 45: 10)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 45: 11-13)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 45: 14)
  Photographs of sixteen posters relating to the cooperative movement in Russia after the revolution. Sent by Pier Hein Hofstra (American Relief Administration representative in the Ufa Ural District) to Mr. Fisher
- VIDEORECORDINGS (Boxes 46-47, Tape cabinet)
  - America's Gift to Famine Stricken Russia, undated (Box 46)
    One VHS videocassette
  - Interview of Yegor T. Gaidar, former counselor to the president of the Russian Federation and first deputy chairman of the government of the Russian Federation, undated
    Includes transcript (incomplete). One VHS videocassette.
  - Russia: Facing the Future, undated
  - How Russia Lives? documentary by Krzystof Zanussi, 1991
  - Red Files, four-part PBS documentary.
    Four VHS videocassettes
    - Secret Soviet Moon Mission
    - Secret Victories of the KGB
    - Soviet Propaganda Machine
    - Soviet Sports Wars (Box 47)
  - Russian Secret, October 1993 events in Moscow
  - #1 – Leon Trotsky in Naples, 1933 (Tape cabinet)
  - #2 – Advertisement for the film Meeting in Orbit, the first joint U.S. and Soviet space flight – Soiuz 19 and Apollo
    Includes fragments of conversations between the cosmonauts, astronauts and people on earth, and press conferences. From the NITSKD (Central film documents archive). One VHS videocassette.
  - #3 – Soviet secret police operations, undated
  - #4 – Television film "Green Street Reds," relating to Soviet espionage in the United States, 1983
    One one-inch videoreel
  - #5-8 – Television film "Messengers from Moscow," relating to the history of Soviet foreign policy, 1994
  - Immortal Fortress: A Look Inside Chechnya's Warrior Culture, Combat Films, New York, 1999
- SOUND RECORDINGS (Record cabinet, Cassette cabinet)
  - One record of Russian songs by the Russian army Leib-Gvardii Kirasirskii Ego Velichestva Polk, undated (Record cabinet)
  - One compact sound cassette with the recorded program from Meeting in Orbit, a film about the first joint U.S. and Soviet space flight – Soiuz 19 and Apollo, undated (Cassette cabinet)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: xx743_a_0009661
    Includes fragments of conversations between the cosmonauts and people on earth, and press conferences. From the NITSKD (Central documents archive).
  - Interview of Socrates Birsky by Myriam Lefloch, Hoover Institution Archives, 2000 July 25; 1.0 sound cassette (Cassette cabinet)
    Use copy reference number: xx743_a_0009665
- COMPACT DISCS (Box 47)
  - Victims of the political terror in the USSR, memorial group, 2001
    One CD-ROM
  - Stalinist firing squad death lists, memorial group, 2002
  - Combat Films documentary: Immortal Fortress: A Look Inside Chechnya's Warrior Culture, 1999
    Use copy reference number: xx743_v_0004367 (VHS and DVD)
    Producer Dodge Billingsley.
- FRAMED ITEMS (Boxes 48-51)
  - 1 Russian icon (Box 48)
  - 2 Russian icons (Box 49)
  - 2 Russian icons (Box 50)
  - 2 Russian icons (Box 51)
- OVERSIZE FILE (Map case)
  - Propaganda, Anti-American. Clippings from Soviet newspapers, 1931
  - Posters reflecting various election campaigns, depicting candidates and their programs
- MEMORABILIA (Boxes 27, 29, 52-53, Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Balloon, "Yeltsin for President" (Box 27)
  - Bandolier
  - 2 banners with portrait of Vladimir Lenin (Box 29)
  - 1 flag
  - Hat with slogan encouraging people to vote (Box 52)
  - Pins for presidential candidates Boris Yeltsin and Martin Shakum
  - 4 t-shirts with slogans supporting Boris Yeltsin for president (Boxes 52-53)
  - Belt buckle with hammer and sickle insignia (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Shapirov, Saetgali, identification card of the KUZBASS independent miners union and lapel pin with insignia of miners
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Boxes 54-70)
- 2017 INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Boxes 71-72)
  - Children's patriotic education material, 2010s (Box 71)
  - Patriotic calendars, 1947-2016
  - Typescript, “Natsional’naia entsiklopediia politsii” (Paris), 1955
  - Miscellaneous leaflets, programs, bulletins, issuances
  - Oni vybirali svobody, documentary on Soviet dissidents, DVD (Box 72)
  - Vohon’ i zbroia, on the Ukrainian Insurgent Army, DVD
  - Turoverskie chteniia, on the modern-day neo-Cossack movement and Cossack history, DVD
  - Vzgliani v glaza voiny, on the Russian Army in WWI, DVD
  - Igry bogov, on neo-pagan revivalism, DVD
  - Vozhd’ i pastyr’, on Stalin and the Orthodox Church, DVD
  - Three CDs with databases on Stalin’s terror, its victims and perpetrators
  - Zima ukhodi (labeled “Winter, go away”), documentary on contemporary political opposition, DVD
  - Chastichnoe pravosudie, on the killing of journalists in the Russian Federation, 1993-2009, DVD
  - Muzei Gulaga, DVD
  - Two disks containing political materials
    One issued by Natsional’no-osvoboditel’noe dvizhenie and the other of unknown origin, but likely also from the radical right.
  - Book entitled Konvoi, containing 3 CDs
  - One sound cassette containing songs of the Liberal-Democratic Party of the Russian Federation